<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<registryObjects xmlns="http://ands.org.au/standards/rif-cs/registryObjects"
                 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                 xsi:schemaLocation="http://ands.org.au/standards/rif-cs/registryObjects https://researchdata.edu.au/documentation/rifcs/schema/registryObjects.xsd">
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AdultVaccinationSurveyDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Adult Vaccination Survey Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2002</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2010</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The Adult Vaccination Survey gatheredinformation about vaccination of adults for the following conditions: influenza, pneumonia, tetanus, shingles. In 2009 the survey also gathered information about vaccination for pertussis ('whooping cough') and the pandemic (H1N1) virus, also known as ‘swine flu’. This survey was run seven times between 2000 and 2010. The AIHW holds the data for 2002, 2004, 2006 and 2009/10.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The survey scope is anationally representative sample of adults. Age ranges vary by survey.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AlcoholandOtherDrugTreatmentServices(NationalMinimumDataSet)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Alcohol and Other Drug Treatment Services (National Minimum Data Set)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2000</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">The Alcohol and Other Drug Treatment Services National Minimum Data Set (AODTS NMDS) emanated from the national forum 'treatment and research - where to from here?' held in 1995 by the Alcohol and Other Drugs Council of Australia. In December 1999 the Commonwealth and state and territory governments through the then National Health Information Management Group endorsed a version of the AODTS NMDS for collection to commence on 1 July 2000. The first data were collected for 2000-01; this was considered a pilot year. The data from 2001-02 onwards contain information about alcohol and other drug treatment services; the clients who use these services; the types of drug problems for which treatment is received and the types of treatment provided.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Government publicly funded alcohol and other drug treatment specialist services, national.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender Indigenous status; SLA; SA2; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralasianPaediatricEndocrineGroupdataset(APEG)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australasian Paediatric Endocrine Group dataset (APEG)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1999</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The APEG dataset contains informationon young people with insulin-treated diabetes aged 0–14 years at the time of diagnosis. As insulin-treated type 2 diabetes is rare in children under 15 years old, most of the children and adolescents listed on the APEG dataset have type 1 diabetes. APEG data are primarily used by the AIHW (together with National Diabetes Services Scheme (NDSS) Registrant data; NDSS Sales data and National Death Index (NDI) data) to create the National (insulin-treated) Diabetes Register (NDR). The collection of the APEG data by AIHW ceased in 2022.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Incident cases of insulin- treated diabetes in young people aged 0–14 years at the time of diagnosis, 1999– 2016, Australia. Due to concerns about the coverage of data in 1999, most reporting begins in 2000.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianandNewZealandDialysisandTransplantRegistry(ANZDATA)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian and New Zealand Dialysis and Transplant Registry (ANZDATA)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1980</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The ANZDATA collects information to monitor dialysis and transplant treatments from all renal units in Australia and New Zealand on all patients receiving kidney replacement therapy where the intention to treat is long-term. The ANZDATA Registry operates under the South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute. ANZDATA compiles data on incidence and prevalence of treated-kidney-failure (previously known as ESKD), complications, comorbidities, and patient deaths. All relevant hospitals and related dialysis units participate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;People registered onAustralia and New Zealand Dialysis and Transplant Register. Collects demographic and status of treatment.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianBurdenofDiseaseDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Burden of Disease Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2003</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The Australian Burden of DiseaseDatabase contains aggregated output of burden of disease metrics from the Australian Burden of Disease Study. This includes Years of life lost (YLL), Years lived with disability (YLD) and Disability adjusted life years (DALY) for around 200 diseases and injuries. It also includes estimates of attributable burden (DALY) for around 30 risk factors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Australian Burdenof Disease Database was established as part of the Australian Burden of Disease Study 2011 to set up the relevant infrastructure to enable efficient and timely ongoing updates by the AIHW as required. The database is updated and added to following the completion of each ABDS. It currently includes national estimates of disease burden and risk factor attribution for 2003, 2011, 2015, 2018. Projected estimates of disease burden are also available for 2022 and 2023. Subnational estimates of disease burden are available for state/territory, remoteness, and socioeconomic group for 2011, 2015 and 2018. Subnational estimates of risk factor attribution are available for socioeconomic group for 2015 and 2018. Indigenous-specific estimates of disease burden and risk factor attribution are available for 2003, 2011 and 2018. All data are available by 5- year age group and sex.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender Indigenous status; RA; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianCancerDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Cancer Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1982</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Australian Cancer Database (ACD) contains data about all new cases of cancer diagnosed in Australia since 1 January 1982, excluding basal and squamous cell carcinomas of the skin. Cancer is a notifiable disease in all Australian states and territories. The relevant legislation requires certain individuals and organisations to notify all new cases of cancer to the jurisdiction's central cancer registry. These registries supply data annually to the AIHW, which cleans and standardises the data, notifies the registries of inter-state duplicates and produces the Australian Cancer Database.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Australian Cancer Database (ACD) contains data about all new cases of cancer diagnosed in Australia since 1 January 1982, excluding basal and squamous cell carcinomas of the skin.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA1; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianDiabetes,ObesityAndLifestyleStudyDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Diabetes, Obesity And Lifestyle Study Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1999</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2005</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The baseline AusDiab study was conducted in 1999-2000 (baseline)and 2005 (follow-up) to determine the prevalence of diabetes, obesity and other risk factors including hypertension and dyslipidaemia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Stratified sample of adults 25 and over residing in 42 randomly chosen Census Collector Districts across the six States and the Northern Territory.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianGovernmenthousingdataset(AGHDS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Government housing data set (AGHDS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2006</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">24/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The AGHDS is a confidentialised unit record file that provides point in time data for income units in receipt of Centrelink social security payments and families receiving Family Tax Benefit (FTB) Part A.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Combines information from numerous Centrelink files to create records at an income unit level, rather than person or household level. An income unit consists of a person, the person’s partner, and any children for whom the couple may receive FTB Part A. Single social security recipients living together in the same household are regarded as separate income units. One person in each income unit is classified as the primary reference person based on sex and the type of payment received. Includes information about type of housing, amount of weekly income, payment type and other characteristics of income units.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianImmunisationRegisterdeidentifiedDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Immunisation Register de identified Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1996</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Australian Immunisation Register (AIR) is a national register that records vaccines given to all people in Australia. The AIR includes vaccines given: (a) under the National Immunisation Program, (b) through school programs, and privately, such as flu or travel.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Originally established as the Australian Childhood Immunisation Register in 1996, to record data on vaccinations provided to children aged up to 7 years, the register was expanded in 2016 to include data for people of all ages. As of 2018 the HPV vaccination register was transferred to the AIR along with records of other school-based immunisation programs. Reporting of adult vaccinations to the AIR was mandated in July 2021 for vaccinations provided under the National Immunisation Program, for influenza and for covid-19, and in December 2022 for Japanese encephalitis virus vacines Reporting of other</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply). There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2010AustralianInfantFeedingSurvey(ANIFS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2010 Australian Infant Feeding Survey (ANIFS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/03/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/03/2011</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The 2010 Australian National Infant Feeding Survey (ANIFS) gathered information about infant feeding practices and attitudes from a sample of mothers and carers in Australia. The survey gathered information about the prevalence and duration of breastfeeding and collected information on other foods consumed by infants. The survey also gathered information about barriers to initiating and continuing breastfeeding and gathered information about perinatal depression.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mothers or primary carers of infants aged up to 24 months. Sample selected from the Medicare enrollment database.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianMesotheliomaRegistrydatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Mesothelioma Registry database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The Australian Mesothelioma Registry (AMR) has been operational since 2011. The AMR was managed by the Cancer Institute New South Wales (CINSW) until 31 August 2017. Since then, the AMR has been managed by the AIHW. The AMR is funded by Safe Work Australia (SWA). Since 2011, the AMR has collected information on new cases of mesothelioma diagnosed in Australia from 1 July 2010. The eight state and territory cancer registries provide incidence and mortality data on new cases of mesothelioma to the AMR. These records include demographic information and details of diagnosis and death. The AMR also collects asbestos exposure information, obtained from consenting mesothelioma patients through a postal questionnaire and telephone interview. The postal questionnaire collects information on a patient’s residential history, occupational history and family history of mesothelioma. The telephone interviews collect additional information, based on responses to the postal questionnaire, to assess the likelihood of asbestos exposure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The notifications data include all cases of mesothelioma diagnosed in Australia since 1 July 2010. Asbestos exposure data includes all consenting patients diagnosed with mesothelioma in Australia since 1 July 2010, who are physically and mentally able to participate.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SA3; SA4; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/AustralianSpinalCordInjuryRegister</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Australian Spinal Cord Injury Register</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#A</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1995</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Data on first and subsequent admissions, from 1 July 1995 to any of the seven specialised spinal units in Australia are being registered prospectively. The register enables measurement of spinal cord injury incidence, study of circumstances and mechanisms.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Australian Spinal Cord Injury Register (ASCIR) is a national register of incident cases of spinal cord injury which occur in Australia and overseas to Australian residents if they are treated in a spinal unit in Australia. Currently, 7 spinal units, all based in public hospitals, contribute data.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/CardiacSurgeryRegister</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Cardiac Surgery Register</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1953</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2001</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Monitoring of cardiac surgery procedure numbers and trends in Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group)</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/ChildProtectionNationalMinimumDataset(CPNMDS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Child Protection National Minimum Dataset (CP NMDS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2012</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Child Protection National Minimum Data Set (CP NMDS) is an annual collection of information on child protection in Australia. It contains data on children who come into contact with State and Territory departments responsible for child protection. The CP NMDS consists of the following data files: client demographics; notifications, investigations, and substantiations; care and protection orders; living arrangements, including children in funded out-of-home care; carer households; data for reporting on National Out-of-Home Care Standards measures; and safety in care. Where possible, data are also collected on sibling relationships. The CP NMDS collection was implemented in 2012–13. Prior to that a national aggregate child protection data collection was used for national child protection reporting (data for this collection began in 1990–91). Some data are still collected in aggregate format in Excel spreadsheets. The data are published annually by AIHW and are also used for the Report on Government Services.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Child protection notifications, investigations, and substantiations; care and protection orders; living arrangements, including children in funded out-of-home care; carer households; national out-of-home care standards; sibling relationships; safety in care.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; Statistical Link Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/CommunityAgedCarePackages(CACP)Census</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Community Aged Care Packages (CACP) Census</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">16/09/2002</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">14/10/2002</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">A census of Community Aged Care Package outlets and care recipients, covering one week of the year. Outlets were asked record assistance provided during 7 consecutive days within the period 16 September 2002 and 14 October 2002.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The census covers clients in whose name a subsidy is claimed AND supplementary clients (also known as excess clients) who are not generally recorded in the CACP administrative by product data collection. Also contains information on service providers that participated in the census.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/CommunityCare</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Community Care</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/1992</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2009</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">This is administrative by product data for the Community Aged Care Packages (CACP) Program, Extended Aged Care at Home (EACH) packages and EACH DEMENTIA (EACHD), and the Transition Care Packages Program. These are all programs designed to enable frail older people with complex care needs to continue living in the community. This is the source of the data for the publication by the AIHW on Community Aged Care packages which has its origins in CACP reporting. Transition care is Commonwealth/State funded but other programs receive recurrent Commonwealth funding. Home and Community Care (HACC) is reported annually by DoHAC and reports are available on their website. The Institute receives a copy of the annual HACC MDS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All recipients of mainstream community aged care packages, EACH and EACHD programs and the Transition Care program.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/CommunityHousing(CH)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Community Housing (CH) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1996</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Community Housing (CH) data collection captures information about CH organisations, the dwellings they manage, and the tenants assisted. CH is rental housing for low- to moderate income or special-needs households. It is managed by community-based organisations that lease properties from government or have received a capital or a recurrent subsidy from government. CH models vary across states and territories, and the housing stock may be owned by a variety of groups including government. The data are supplied by state and territory housing departments on an annual basis. Since 1996–97, the AIHW has compiled CH data from state and territory housing departments on an annual basis. These data help to describe the performance of the current National Housing and Homelessness Agreement and the former National Affordable Housing Agreement and Commonwealth-State Housing Agreement. The data collection has evolved over time. Changes have occurred to data collection scope, procedures, data items and underlying definitions and concepts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;CH includes tenancy (rental) units under management of a CH organisation, excluding Indigenous CH organisations. CH excludes dwellings: • where the tenancy is managed under: Public Housing; State and Territory Owned and Managed Indigenous Housing; Indigenous CH; or the Crisis Accommodation Program. • no longer administered by a CH organisation at 30 June of the reference financial year (including dwellings demolished, sold or otherwise disposed of). • not yet available to CH organisations at 30 June of the reference financial year (e.g. under construction or being purchased). Additional jurisdiction specific inclusions and exclusions reflect: different definitions of CH in legislation; difficulties in identifying some organisations e.g. those not registered or funded by the state/ territory housing authority; inconsistencies in reporting e.g. inclusion of transitional housing and National Rental Affordability Scheme dwellings owned or managed by CH organisations. Currently: • NSW, Vic, WA, SA, Tas and ACT supply unit record level data, including details on individuals, organisations, dwellings and associated tenancies of the organisations. • Qld supplies aggregate data supplemented by unit record administrative data for funded organisations, properties and current waitlist applications. • NT supplies finalised aggregate data, including dwelling and organisational level data, but not information on individual tenancies or persons. • Data are incomplete for some jurisdictions due to non/under-reporting by CH organisations.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/CoronaryAngioplastyRegister</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Coronary Angioplasty Register</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1980</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2001</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Monitoring of coronary angioplasty numbers and trends in Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/DayTherapyCentre(DTC)Census</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Day Therapy Centre (DTC) Census</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">21/10/2002</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">17/11/2002</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">A census of Day Therapy Centres and their clients conducted on behalf of the Department of Health and Aged Care. Outlets were asked to record assistance provided to clients during the census period (21 October to 17 November 2002).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The census contains an individual record for each client receiving service during the census, including demographic and circumstance data (accommodation, carer details), health conditions dependency status, dementia status, types of therapy and the conditions for which therapy is provided, and cessation details. Data collected for Day Therapy Centres includes contact details, co-location with aged care facilities, source of clients (residential care and/or community) and the catchment they are drawn from, main referral sources, staffing profiles and range of therapies provided, the care planning process and fees policy.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Dental:AdultDentalProgramsSurvey</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Dental: Adult Dental Programs Survey</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1901</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Examine the nature of dental care received by patients through public funded dental programs in Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement/>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Dental:ChildDentalHealthSurvey</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Dental: Child Dental Health Survey</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1901</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Measure caries prevalence in Australian children.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement/>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Dental:NationalDentalTelephoneInterviewStudy,1994</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Dental: National Dental Telephone Interview Study, 1994</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1994</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/1994</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Provide information on dental health and access to dental services of the Australian population. For those who have attended a dental practitioner in the last 12 months a sub sample are included in a survey of dental satisfaction to identify the magnitude&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement/>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Dental:TheChildFluorideStudy</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Dental: The Child Fluoride Study</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1901</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Evaluate the effectiveness of waterfluoridation in the prevention of caries in a child population.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement/>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/DisabilityServicesNationalMinimumDataSet(DSNMDS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Disability Services National Minimum Data Set (DS NMDS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#D</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1994</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2019</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">Since 1991, data was collected and reported on disability support services in Australia have been provided under four national disability agreements. The Commonwealth/State Disability Agreement Minimum Data Set (CSDA MDS) collection was set up as a 'snapshot' data collection in 1994, following the signing of the first CSDA in 1991. The second CSDA, signed in 1998, reflected significant changes which meant the CSDA MDS collection needed to be redesigned, including changing the collection to be a full year data collection. In 2002-03, the redeveloped CSDA MDS became the Commonwealth State/Territory Disability Agreement National Minimum Data Set (CSTDA NMDS), and the first full financial year of data collection took place between 1 July 2003 and 30 June 2004. The National Disability Agreement (NDA) replaced the CSTDA on 1 January 2009. As a result of the implementation of the NDA, from 2009-10 the CSTDA NMDS was renamed the DS NMDS. From 1 July 2013, state and territory based disability support services provided under the NDA were progressively transitioned over to the National Disability Insurance Scheme (NDIS). This has meant that 2018-19 was the last year for which DS NMDS was data collected and reported.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Covers specialist disability support services provided under the National Disability Agreement.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/ExtendedAgedCareatHome(EACH)Census</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Extended Aged Care at Home (EACH) Census</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#E</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/05/2002</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/05/2002</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">This is a census of the clients receiving Extended Aged Care at Home Packages and the service providers. The census covers a one-week period in May 2002.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The census covers clients who are receiving EACH packages and the service outlets that provide the assistance. Individual client data includes demographic and circumstance data (accommodation, carer details), dependency status, dementia status, types and amounts of assistance received, equipment used, leave details and cessation details. Data collected for service providers includes contact details, type of provider, profit status, and the use of brokerage for service provision.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/GeneralTreatmentDentalDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>General Treatment Dental Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#G</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The General Treatment Dental (GT Dental) data collection is a collection of dental service records for which private health insurers have paid benefits. The data are supplied to the Department of Health and Aged Care by private health insurers. The collection contains de identified unit record level data with information related to patient demographics (derived age, sex, postcode), procedure type, number of dental service items, charges, and benefits paid.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dataset contains information about patient demographics (derived age, sex, postcode), the ADA code of dental service items, charges and benefits paid.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/HomeAndCommunityCare(HACC)MDS</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Home And Community Care (HACC) MDS</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2001</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2009</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Contains service provision data forHACC. There are two files for each yearly collection. While there are quarterly files on the system for some earlier years only annual files are considered as official HACC data. Extract 1 contains all unlinked unit records from individual agency; Extract 2 contains internally linked data according to the statistical linkage key.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data is collected on all care recipients and carers receiving HACC funded assistance. Group service provision to unidentified recipients is not collected (e.g. group information sessions).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/HomePurchaseAssistance(HPA)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Home Purchase Assistance (HPA) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The HPA data collection captures information about the recipients of HPA and instances of HPA assistance. HPA is administered by each state/territory housing authority and provides a range of financial assistance to eligible households to improve their access to, and maintain, home ownership. Since 1997–98, the AIHW has compiled HPA data from states and territories on an annual basis. The data help to describe the performance of the current National Housing and Homelessness Agreement and the former National Affordable Housing Agreement and Commonwealth- State Housing Agreement. The data collection has evolved over time, with changes to the data collection scope, procedures, data items collected and underlying definitions and concepts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Includes: • direct lending (including government loans, shared equity loans and bridging loans) • deposit assistance • interest rate assistance • mortgage relief • other assistance grants. Excludes: • non-financial assistance, for example home purchase advisory and counselling services • home renovation and/or maintenance services • relocation or start up assistance • sale to tenant programs • provision of housing or any share of it • expense incurred in providing assistance to a household that is not the value of financial assistance directly received by the household • any aspect of a shared equity loan that is not direct lending, deposit assistance, interest rate assistance or mortgage relief • any assistance not provided expressly for purchasing a home.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/HospitalCasemixProtocol(HCP)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Hospital Casemix Protocol (HCP) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The HCP data collection is a legislated data collection for all private health insurance funded admitted patient separations for which private health insurers have paid benefits. The data is collected by public and private hospitals, including day facilities, and then supplied to private health insurers, who in turn then submit the data to the Department of Health and Aged Care.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;De-identified information on admitted patient separations including information on patient demographics, clinical information, hospital charges, medical services, medical charges, prosthetic items, prosthetic charges, private health insurance and Medicare benefits, and consumer out-of pocket expenses.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/HospitalDementiaServices(HDS)SurveyData</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Hospital Dementia Services (HDS) Survey Data</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">NSW</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2006</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2007</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The HDS survey obtained information about the availability of aged care and dementia services in New South Wales public hospitals for the period 1 July 2006 to 30 June 2007.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The survey sample isall public hospitals in New South Wales for the period 1 July 2006 to 30 June 2007. The overall response rate was 83%.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/HospitalUtilisationandCostsstudy</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Hospital Utilisationand Costs study</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1985</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/1993</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Predecessor to National Public Hospital Establishments Database and National Hospital Morbidity Database&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All States financial data for public hospitals and morbidity data for all hospitals.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Hostels(Pre1997Reforms)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Hostels (Pre 1997Reforms)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#H</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">1/12/1989</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/1999</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">Prior to the Aged Care Act 1997, nursing home and hostels operated under separate Acts, with separate support computer systems. Limited file descriptions for the hostel holdings are available from the Ageing and Aged Care Unit.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Residents of hostelsuntil October 1997</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/IndigenousCommunityHousing(ICH)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Indigenous Community Housing (ICH) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#I</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2003</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Indigenous Community Housing (ICH) data collection captures information about ICH organisations (ICHOs), the dwellings they manage, and tenants assisted. ICHOs include community organisations such as resource agencies and land councils, which may have a range of functions, however, are included in ICH provided that they manage housing for Indigenous people. ICHOs may either directly manage the dwellings they own or sublease tenancy management services to the relevant state/territory housing department or another organisation. Since 2003–04, the AIHW has compiled ICH data from state and territory housing departments on an annual basis. These data help to describe the performance of Indigenous housing programs. The data collection has evolved over time, including changes to the data collection scope, procedures, data items and underlying definitions and concepts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Inclusions: dwellings that are targeted to Indigenous people and ICHOs that provide medium- to long-term housing tenure to tenants. Excludes dwellings: • managed under Community Housing, Public Housing, State Owned and Managed Indigenous Housing, or the Crisis Accommodation Program • no longer under the administration of an ICHO at 30 June of the reference year (including dwellings demolished, sold or otherwise disposed of) • not yet available to the ICHO at 30 June of the reference year (such as those still under construction or being purchased). Apart from the following, the data collection focuses on dwellings managed by funded ICHOs only (for NSW, this means excluding not actively registered ICHOs): • Number of permanent dwellings managed by funded and unfunded organisations at 30 June • Number of funded and unfunded ICHOs at 30 June. There is no ICH program in the ACT.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Medical</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Medical</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; NSW</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1986</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2009</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the medical labour force. All years from 1995 are loaded and available. Earlier data stored on CD.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All medical practitioners renewing their professional registration.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Nursing</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Nursing</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; NSW</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1995</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2009</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the nursing labour force.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All enrolled and registered nurses renewing their professional enrolment/registration.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:OccupationalTherapy</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Occupational Therapy</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1998</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2003</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the occupational therapy labour force in Vic, Qld, WA, ACT and NT. Occupational therapy data for 1998 survey, comprising Vic., Qld, WA, ACT and NT only.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All occupational therapists renewing their professional registration in those jurisdictions where a registration board exists. The national association also assists with the distribution of the survey to members in some jurisdictions without registration boards. The 2002- 2003 Occupational Therapy Labour Force Survey was distributed to registered occupational therapists in Queensland, South Australia, and the Northern Territory and to members of OT Australia in the other states and the Australian Capital Territory because these jurisdictions didn't have a registration board in 2002-03. For 2002- 2003 there were 3,769 valid responses provided to the AIHW for analysis (Table 3). In the absence of an accurate estimate of the total population of occupational therapists it was not feasible to weight the responses to the survey.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Optometry</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Optometry</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1991</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/1999</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics andstructure of the optometrist labour force derived from Medicare data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All optometristsrenewing their professional registration</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Pharmacy</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Pharmacy</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1994</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2003</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the pharmacy labour force.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All pharmacists renewing their professional registration.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Physiotherapy</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Physiotherapy</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1993</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2002</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the physiotherapy labour force in 1993, 1998 and 2002. In 2002 not distributed in Tas, WA and possibly not NT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All physiotherapists renewing their professional registration.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/LabourForce:Podiatry</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Labour Force: Podiatry</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#L</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1992</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2003</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Contains data on the demographics and structure of the podiatry labour force. The following exclusions apply: 1992 data - excludes NT and ACT (no podiatry registration board) 1994 data - excludes NT and ACT (no podiatry registration board) 1999 data - excludes NT (no podiatry registration board) 2003 data - excludes NT (no podiatry registration board) and WA and ACT (not distributed)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All podiatrists renewing their professional registration.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/MaternityModelofCareDataSet</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Maternity Model ofCare Data Set</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#M</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2018</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/04/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Model of Care Data Set (MoC DS) is a national collection of data about the maternity models of care available at each maternity service. The data elements reflect the characteristics of these models including, the women a model is designed for, the maternity carers involved and the role they play, and aspects of how and where care is provided. Each model of care is classified into 1 of 11 model categories based on these characteristics. This data set reflects maternity care at a service level but can also be used by maternity services to populate person-level models of care items in the National Perinatal Data Collection. Summary information about the models of care available at each maternity service can be found at the MaCCS website https://maccs.aihw.gov.au/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scope of this data set includes models of maternity care available to pregnant and birthing women. Maternity services classify their models of care using the Maternity Care Classification System (MaCCS). The MaCCS provides a standardised nomenclature for the collection. The data elements describe the different characteristics of models of maternity care around 3 domains: • the women a model is designed for • the carers working in the model • aspects of how and where care is provided. This collection reflects maternity care at a service level but can also be used by maternity services to populate person-level models of care items in the National Perinatal Data Collection. The development of the MaCCS and the data set were undertaken as part of the National Maternity Data Development Project under the guidance of an expert advisory group. This data set is not mandated for collection. For more information see https://meteor.aihw.go v.au/content/559937</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/MedicalIndemnityNationalCollection(PrivateSector)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Medical Indemnity National Collection (Private Sector)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#M</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2004</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2013</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Medical Indemnity National Collection (Private sector).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All claim records required to be reported by MIIs to the Australian Prudential Regulation Authority (APRA) are required to be reported to the AIHW, along with a small number of claims that pertain to when the MIIs were organised as medical defence organisations. The reporting MIIs have changed over time due to business combinations and the entry of a new MII (In vivo) in 2005-06 (subsequently combined with Medical Insurance Group Australia in 2012-13).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Unit records are not available, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/MedicalIndemnityNationalCollectionPublicSector(MINCPS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Medical Indemnity National Collection Public Sector (MINC PS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#M</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2003</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2013</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Medical Indemnity National Collection Public Sector (MINC PS)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All medical indemnity claims open at any time during a reference year are reported for that reference year.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/MedicareBenefitsSchedule(MBS)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Medicare Benefits Schedule (MBS) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#M</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/02/1984</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Medicare Benefits Schedule (MBS) data collection contains information on services that qualify for a benefit under the Health Insurance Act 1973 and for which a claim has been processed. The database comprises information about MBS claims (including benefits paid), patients and service providers. AIHW has access to a view of the dataset held by the Australian Government Department of Health and Aged Care for approved studies, including data linkage projects (see AIHW Data Integration Services Centre). The dataset is owned and managed by the Department of Health and Aged Care. The Department has issued a Public Interest Certificate approving AIHW access to MBS claims data for research and statistical purposes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;MBS claims data are an administrative by product of Services Australia administration of the Medicare fee-for service payment system. MBS services are available to all Australian residents who hold a current Medicare card and overseas visitors from countries with which Australia has a Reciprocal Health Care Agreement (RHCA).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Unit records are not available there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/National(insulintreated)DiabetesRegister</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National (insulin treated)Diabetes Register</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1999</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The National (insulin-treated) Diabetes Register (NDR) aims to record all new cases of people who began to use insulin to treat their diabetes since 1 January 1999. The NDR includes people with type 1, type 2, gestational and other forms of diabetes. Data for the NDR are sourced from the National Diabetes Services Scheme (NDSS) and the Australasian Paediatric Endocrine Groups (APEG) state and territory registers. The collection of APEG data ceased in 2022. The NDR is now derived using only the NDSS. For more information about the NDR and how it is derived, see the Data Quality Statement&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Incident cases of insulin- treated diabetes, 1999-2022, Australia</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SA3; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalAdoptionsDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National AdoptionsData Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1990</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Aggregate data collected annually by financial year, are provided by state and territory departments responsible for adoptions and by the Department of Home Affairs. Information collected relates to children placed for adoption and those who had an adoption order finalised. Some data are also collected on children whose adoption order was finalised during the previous financial year. Collected data include characteristics of adopted children, their parents and their adoptive families. Collected associated administrative process data include applications and vetoes for contact and information exchange, type of authority responsible for the adoption, type of consent provided for the adoption, median time for intercountry adoption processes, status of adoption orders at 30 June, and number of adoption specific visas issued. Data are published annually in the AIHW Adoptions Australia report series including online data visualisations, aggregate data tables, and in a topic summary for Australia’s welfare.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data relate to children placed with adoptive families during a financial year and those who had an adoption order finalised during a financial year. Additional data are also collected on adoption specific visas issued during a financial year (these data may relate to adoptions that occurred in previous years).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status;</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalAgedCareDataClearinghouse(NACDC)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Aged Care Data Clearinghouse (NACDC)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The National Aged Care Data Clearinghouse (NACDC) is an independent and central repository of national aged care data. It brings together information on people receiving aged care and the services and organisations providing care. It largely contains administrative by-product data from the Department of Health and Aged Care. The NACDC comprises more than 130 tables in relational databases. Most of these relate to government-funded aged care programs operating under the Aged Care Act 1997. The NACDC includes activity data for home support, home care, residential care, transition care, short-term restorative care and aged care eligibility assessments.. It also includes other data sources related to quality indicators for residential aged care, consumer experience in residential aged care and aged care workforce. Most of the activity data is refreshed annually with data from the Department of Health and Aged Care’s Aged Care Data Warehouse. Data for quality indicators are supplied quarterly. Other data sources are updated on a less regular or ad hoc basis.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Administrative data on government funded aged care programs, including home support, home care, residential care, transition care, short term restorative care and aged care eligibility assessments. Details available on services, providers, care recipients, episodes of care and assessments. Indicator data collected on a quarterly basis from all approved providers of residential care services for quality indicators defined in the National Aged Care Mandatory Quality Indicator Program Manual, which is available on the Department of Health and Aged Care website at https://www.health.go v.au/resources/collect ions/national-aged care-mandatory quality-indicator program-manual Survey data from the 2017–18 and 2018– 19 Consumer Experience Surveys, collected from a sample of care recipients in residential care facilities as part of the (typically) 3-yearly accreditation site visits. Survey data from the 2022–23 Aged Care Provider Workforce Survey, collected from a sample of government-funded aged care providers.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SA2; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalCommunityMentalHealthCareDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Community Mental Health Care Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2000</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Service contact data at the patient level for public sector specialised community mental health services.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Specialised public mental health services that are classified as 'ambulatory'. They do not include admitted patient mental health care services, support services that are not specialised mental health care services (e.g. accommodation support services), and services provided by non-government organisations and residential care services.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalCommunityMentalHealthEstablishmentsDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Community Mental Health Establishments Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1998</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2000</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">National collection of data on communitybased mental health services, including both residential and ambulatory establishments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data for specialised psychiatric services that deliver ambulatory services, in both institutional and community settings and/or community-based residential care. It does not extend to services provided to patients who are in general (non specialised) care who may be receiving treatment or rehabilitation for psychiatric conditions.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalCongenitalAnomaliesDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Congenital Anomalies Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2016</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Provides information on infants with congenital anomalies in Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The NCADC is a national data collection on babies with a congenital anomaly. It is based on cases of congenital anomalies reported to state and territory data collections including congenital anomaly registers, perinatal data collections and admitted patient data collections. The scope of the NCADC includes births (both live births and stillbirths) with a diagnosed congenital anomaly and terminations of pregnancy due to a congenital anomaly (if this is available). This includes conditions in the relevant edition of the ICD10-AM, including Chapter 17 (Q00- Q99), P35 (congenital viral diseases) and P371 (congenital toxoplasmosis).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply) Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalDeathIndex</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Death Index</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1980</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The National Death Index (NDI) is a data base developed and maintained by the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare, in Canberra. The data base is a listing of all deaths that have occurred in Australia since 1980. It is an invaluable tool for epidemiologists and clinicians in following up research cohorts using record linkage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All deaths in Australiasince 1980.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth), Sex/gender, Address, SA1, SA2, SA3, SA4</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalDiabetesServicesScheme(de-identifieddata)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Diabetes Services Scheme (de-identified data)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1987</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/03/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">NDSS registrants and sales datasets, related to receiving information and subsidised consumable products related to managing diabetes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The National Diabetes Services Scheme (NDSS) is an initiative of the Australian Government that commenced in 1987 and is administered by Diabetes Australia. The NDSS aims to enhance the capacity of people with diabetes to understand and self manage their life with diabetes, and access services, support and subsidised diabetes products. The NDSS is the most comprehensive register of people diagnosed with type 1, type 2, gestational and other forms of diabetes in Australia.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/1998NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveyMasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>1998 National Drug Strategy Household Survey Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#1</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/06/1998</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/09/1998</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the sixth in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the first to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 14 years and over. There were 10,030 completed responses in 1998. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Non-institutionalisedpersons aged 14 years and over from all states and territories. Foreign language interviews were not conducted.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2001NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurvey</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2001 National Drug Strategy Household Survey</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2001</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/11/2001</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the seventh in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the second to&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Non-institutionalisedpersons aged 14 years and over from</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics,</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/MasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#M</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text"/>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: </description>
         <description type="full">be conducted by the AIHW, but the first to be conducted fully as an AIHW function. It is a national household survey of non institutionalised persons aged 14 years and over. There were 26,744 completed responses in 2001. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;all states and territories. Foreign language interviews were not conducted.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: status; SLA; RA; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2004NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveyMasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2004 National Drug Strategy Household Survey Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2004</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">8/11/2004</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the eighth in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the third to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 12 years and over. There were 29,445 completed responses in 2004. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Non-institutionalisedpersons aged 14 years and over from all states and territories. Foreign language interviews were not conducted.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2007NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveyMasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2007 National Drug Strategy Household Survey Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">19/06/2007</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">28/10/2007</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the ninth in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the fourth to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non institutionalised persons aged 12 years and over. There were 23,356 completed responses in 2007. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research and the Social Research Centre.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Non-institutionalisedpersons aged 12 years or older or 14 years or older (as specified) from all states and territories. Foreign language interviews were not conducted.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2010NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveyMasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2010 National Drug Strategy Household Survey Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">29/04/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">14/09/2010</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the tenth in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the fifth to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 12 years and over. There were 26,648 completed responses in 2010. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The estimates for 2010 contained in this publication are based on information obtained from people aged 12 years or older or 14 years or older (as specified) from all states and territories. The scope of the survey was residential households, and excluded institutional settings, hostels, motels and homeless people. Foreign language interviews were not conducted.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2013NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveyMasterUnitRecordFile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2013 National Drug Strategy Household Survey Master Unit Record File</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/07/2013</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">1/12/2013</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the eleventh in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the sixth to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 12 years and over. There were 23,855 completed responses in 2013. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Private dwellings frompeople aged 12 years or older. Excluded from sampling were non private dwellings (hotels, motels, boarding houses, etc.) and institutional settings (hospitals, nursing homes, other clinical settings such as drug and alcohol rehabilitation centres, prisons, military establishments, and university halls of residence). Homeless persons were also excluded as well as the territories of Jervis Bay, Christmas Island and Cocos Island.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA1; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2016NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveymasterunitrecordfile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2016 National Drug Strategy Household Survey master unit record file</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">21/06/2016</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">29/11/2016</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is twelfth in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the seventh to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 12 years and over. There were 23,772 completed responses in 2016. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Private dwellings frompeople aged 12 years or older. Excluded from sampling were non private dwellings (hotels, motels, boarding houses, etc.) and institutional settings (hospitals, nursing homes, other clinical settings such as drug and alcohol rehabilitation centres, prisons, military establishments, and university halls of residence). Homeless persons were also excluded as well as the territories of Jervis Bay, Christmas Island and Cocos Island.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA1; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2019NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurveymasterunitrecordfile</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2019 National Drug Strategy Household Survey master unit record file</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">08/04/2019</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">22/09/2019</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the 13th in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the 8th to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 14 years and over. There were 22,272 completed responses in 2019. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Private dwellings frompeople aged 14 years or older. Excluded from sampling were non private dwellings (hotels, motels, boarding houses, etc.) and institutional settings (hospitals, nursing homes, other clinical settings such as drug and alcohol rehabilitation centres, prisons, military establishments, and university halls of residence). Homeless persons were also excluded as well as the territories of Jervis Bay, Christmas Island and Cocos Island.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex;/gender Indigenous status; RA; SA1; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/2022-2023NationalDrugStrategyHouseholdSurvey</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>2022-2023 National Drug Strategy Household Survey</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#2</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">20/07/2022</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/05/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">This is the 14th in a series of surveys auspices by the National Drug Strategy (and its predecessors) and the 9th to be conducted by the AIHW. It is a national household survey of non-institutionalised persons aged 14 years and over. There were 21,663 completed responses in 2022-2023. Fieldwork was conducted by Roy Morgan Research.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Private dwellings from people aged 14 years or older. Excluded from sampling were non private dwellings (hotels, motels, boarding houses, etc.) and institutional settings (hospitals, nursing homes, other clinical settings such as drug and alcohol rehabilitation centres, prisons, military establishments and university halls of residence). Persons who were homeless were also excluded as well as the territories of Jervis Bay, Christmas Island and Cocos Island.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA1; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA; Statistical linkage key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications; Summary tables published in electronic form; Statistics; Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply); Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalElectiveSurgeryTargetDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Elective Surgery Target Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2011</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2015</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">Census and removal elective surgery waiting list entries for the purposes of reporting the National Elective Surgery Targets as part of the National Partnership Agreement on Improving Public Hospital Services&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hospitals reporting public hospital Elective surgery waiting lists</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalHandHygieneDataSet</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Hand Hygiene Data Set</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National, National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/04/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The data are derived from audits of hand hygiene ‘moments’ that were conducted in public hospitals between April 2010 and June 2020 under the National Hand Hygiene Initiative, established by the Australian Commission on Safety and Quality in Health Care. Data are presented by moment type and by health care worker type.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The National Hand Hygiene Initiative (NHHI) aims to educate and promote correct hand hygiene practice in all Australian hospitals and includes auditing and reporting processes for hospitals to measure how they are performing against the benchmark determined by the Australian Health Ministers Advisory Council. This benchmark has been progressively increasing and is now set at 80%.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Unit records are not available, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalHealthWorkforceDataSet(NHWDS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Health Workforce Data Set (NHWDS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">28/04/2011</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/10/2017</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The NHWDS is a combination of registration and survey data collected through the registration renewal process for registered health practitioners.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Registered Health practitioners in these professions: •Nurse • Midwife • Chiropractor • Dental practitioner • Medical practitioner • Osteopath • Optometrist • Pharmacist • Physiotherapist • Podiatrist • Psychologist • Occupational therapist • Medical radiation practitioner • Chinese medicine practitioner • Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander health practitioner. Paramedicine to be added from late 2018 (to be available mid 2019)</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth) ; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SA2; SA3; SA4; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalHospitalsDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National HospitalsData Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1993</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2019</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">This collection includes the major national hospitals databases held by the AIHW, including: • The National Hospital Morbidity Database (NHMD), a compilation of episode-level records from admitted patient morbidity data collection systems inAustralian public and private hospitals. • The National Public Hospital Establishments Database (NPHED), which holds information on public hospital resources and includes information reported for public hospitals, Local hospital networks (LHNs) and state and territory health authorities. • The National Non-admitted Patient Emergency Department Care Database (NNAPEDCD), a compilation of episode- level records (including waiting times for care) for non-admitted patients registered for care in emergency departments in selected public hospitals. • The National Elective Surgery Waiting Times Data Collection (NESWTDC), which holds episode-level information on patients added to or removed from elective surgery waiting lists managed by public hospitals. • The National Non-Admitted Patient Care (aggregate) Database (NNAP(agg)D), which holds clinic-level information on non- admitted patient care provided by public hospitals, LHNs and selected other public hospital services managed by state and territory health authorities. • The National Non-admitted Patient (episode-level) Database (NNAP(el)D), which holds episode-level information on non-admitted patient care provided by public hospitals, LHNs and selected other public hospital services managed by state and territory health authorities. • 1/1/2011-30/6/2013: The National Emergency Access Target Database (NEATD) is a compilation of electronic records of non-admitted patient service episodes for the purposes of reporting the National Emergency Access Targets as part of the National Partnership Agreement on Improving Public Hospital Services. • 1/1/2011-30/6/2015: The National Elective Surgery Targets Database (NESTD) is census and removal elective surgery waiting list entries for the purposes of reporting the National Elective Surgery Targets as part of the National Partnership Agreement on Improving Public Hospital Services. 2005-2013: National collection of occasions of service provided in outpatient clinics of public hospitals that are classified as either principal referral and specialist women’s and children’s hospitals and large hospitals (Peer Group A or B) as reported in the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare’s Australian Hospital Statistics publication from the preceding financial year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scope of data held under the National Hospitals Data Collection vary by database and over time. Please refer to the relevant metadata for further information.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SLA; RA; SA1; SA2; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply). There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalKeyPerformanceIndicators(nKPIs)forFirstNations-specificprimaryhealthcare</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Key Performance Indicators (nKPIs) for First Nations - specific primary health care</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2012</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The national Key Performance Indicators (nKPIs) are a set of indicators reported by organisations receiving funding under the Australian Government's Indigenous Australians’ Health Programme (IAHP) to deliver comprehensive and culturally appropriate primary health care services to Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander (First Nations) people. Data are collected against set of indicators focusing on maternal and child health, preventative health, and chronic disease management. The collection commenced in June 2012 and is ongoing with data being collected every 6 months from over 200 First Nations-specific primary health care organisations across Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Collected from the over 200 organisations funded under the Australian Government's Indigenous Australians’ Health Programme (IAHP), data are counts of First Nations regular clients (those who attended an organisation 3 times in 2 years) against a set of indicators focusing on maternal and child health; preventative health; and chronic disease management. Organisations reporting to the nKPI collection may see a mix of First Nations and non-Indigenous clients. Some of these are considered regular clients of the organization. The nKPI indicators include only data for First Nations regular clients.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalMaternalMortalityDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Maternal Mortality Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2006</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Data is collected for all maternal deaths (up to and including 42 days post-partum) occurring in each state or territory. Data collection commenced from 1 January 2013. Retrospective data for 2006-2012 has also been provided by most jurisdictions. Late maternal deaths (occurring from 43 days postpartum up to and including 365 days post-partum) are optional and can be supplied if the state/territory wishes to do so.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data is collected for all maternal deaths (up to and including 42 days postpartum) occurring in the state or territory. Data are also requested on late maternal deaths (occurring from 43- 365 days after end of pregnancy) where available.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalMentalHealthEstablishmentsDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Mental Health Establishments Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2005</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">National collection of establishment level data for specialised mental health services.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scope of the MHE NMDS is all specialised mental health services managed by, or in receipt of funds from, State or Territory health authorities</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalMortalityDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Mortality Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1964</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The National Mortality Database (NMD) holds records for deaths in Australia from 1964. The database comprises information about causes of death and other characteristics of the person, such as sex, age at death, area of usual residence and Indigenous status.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All deaths in Australia.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalOpioidPharmacotherapyStatisticsAnnualData(NOPSAD)collection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Opioid Pharmacotherapy Statistics Annual Data (NOPSAD) collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2004</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The main purpose of the NOPSAD collection is to aggregate standardised jurisdictional data on the number of clients accessing pharmacotherapy for the treatment of opioid dependence, the number of prescribers participating in the delivery of pharmacotherapy treatment, and quantitative information about the prescribing sector. As such, national information on pharmacotherapy, on a snapshot day each year, can be reported.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The collection covers the provision of opioid pharmacotherapy treatment, the practitioners who prescribe the treatment, the dosing sites who dispense the pharmacotherapy drugs, and the clients receiving the opioid pharmacotherapy treatment. The following pharmacotherapies are currently recommended for the treatment of opioid dependency: Methadone hydrochloride Methadone Syrup®, Biodone Forte ® Buprenorphine Subutex® Buprenorphine/ Naloxone Suboxone®, buprenorphine as long acting injections (Buvidal® and Sublocade®).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender Indigenous status; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalPerinatalDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Perinatal Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1991</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The National Perinatal Data Collection (NPDC) is a national population-based cross-sectional collection of data on pregnancy and childbirth. The data are based on births reported to the perinatal data collection in each state and territory in Australia. Midwives and other birth attendants, using information obtained from mothers and from hospital or other records, complete notification forms for each birth. A standard de-identified extract is provided to the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare (AIHW) on an annual basis to form the NPDC.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Includes live births and stillbirths, where gestational age is at least 20 weeks or birthweight is at least 400 grams, except in Victoria and Western Australia, where births are included if gestational age is at least 20 weeks or, if gestation is unknown, birthweight is at least 400 grams. See also NPDC Data Quality Statement National Perinatal Data Collection, 2021: Quality Statement (aihw.gov.au)) (METEOR 778883)</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply). There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalPerinatalMortalityDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Perinatal Mortality Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2013</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The National Perinatal Mortality Data Collection (NPMDC) is a national collection of all stillbirths and neonatal deaths occurring in the state or territory of at least 20 weeks gestation or 400 grams birthweight. Stillbirths include Fetus Papyraceous and Fetus Compressus if they meet the definition of the National Perinatal Data Collection.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All stillbirths and neonatal deaths occurring in the state or territory of at least 20 weeks gestation or 400 grams birthweight. Stillbirths include Fetus Papyraceous and Fetus Compressus if they meet the definition of the National Perinatal Data Collection.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply). There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalPhysicalActivitySurveys</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Physical Activity Surveys</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">10/11/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">8/12/2000</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The 1997, 1999 and 2000 National Physical Activity Surveys collected information about physical activity patterns in Australian adults. Activity levels were measured against the National Physical Activity Guidelines. The survey also measured awareness of physical activity campaigns and media messages that were current at the time of each survey. The 1997 survey was called the Active Australia National Physical Activity Survey.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Adults aged 18-75 from households randomly selected from the White Pages.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group;; Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalPrisonerHealthDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Prisoner Health Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2009</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The National Prisoner Health Data Collection (NPHDC) is held by the AIHW. The collection has been held in 2009, 2010, 2012, 2015, 2018 and 2022. The 2022 collection was originally planned for 2021 but delayed due to COVID-19. The scope includes various data items concerning prison entrants and prison dischargees over a two-week period, clinic attendances, medications administered and some general information about prisons and their operations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Australian public andprivate prisons in participating jurisdictions.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalResidentialMentalHealthCareDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Residential Mental Health Care Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2004</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Episodes of residential care for residents in all government-funded mental health services. Episodes of residential mental health care at patient level.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Episodes of residential care for residents in all government-funded mental health services. The scope of the NMDS specifically excludes residential care services that are in receipt of funding under the Aged Care Act and subject to Commonwealth reporting requirements.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalRheumaticHeartDiseasedatacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Rheumatic Heart Disease data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">NSW; QLD; WA; SA; NT</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2016</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Official</description>
         <description type="full">The National Rheumatic Heart Disease Data Collection (NRHDDC) comprises information from jurisdictional registers of notified cases of acute rheumatic fever/rheumatic heart disease (ARF/RHD). It is a de-identified population-based collection, initiated as part of the Australian Rheumatic Fever Strategy 2009, funded by the Australian Government Department of Health and Aged Care. The data collection will enable reporting on the Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) of the Strategy, reporting local level data to jurisdictional registers and supporting relevant data development activities. This will contribute to efforts to reduce the incidence of ARF and RHD in Australia, which are among the highest in the world. Data from NSW are sent to the AIHW also, though this is not funded through the RFS.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The information collected is de identified unit record data about living and deceased individuals affected by ARF and/or RHD. The collection contains demographic data (age, sex, Indigenous status), information about clinical diagnosis (diagnosis and notification dates), disease progression, clinical severity, secondary prophylaxis, and surgical management. The data will be used in at least four ways. - to monitor and report program effectiveness in the detection and management of ARF/RHD in Australia, as measured by the KPIs under the Rheumatic Fever Strategy. - for reporting against the relevant indicators in the Health Performance Framework report. - for reporting against the relevant indicators in the Better Cardiac Care report. - Regular (unpublished) jurisdictional-level data reports, as per jurisdictional requirements, to be supplied to individual jurisdictions.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalSeclusionandRestraintDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Seclusionand Restraint Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Aggregate data on seclusion and restraint events, episodes of care, mental health care days, episodes with seclusion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Public sector specialised acute mental health hospital services</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalSocialHousingSurvey(NSHS)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Social Housing Survey (NSHS)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2005</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The National Social Housing Survey is a survey of social housing tenants which complements administrative data collected by social housing providers and includes information on tenants and their social housing experiences.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Participants are randomly sampled from social housing programs e.g., Public Housing (PH), State Owned and Managed Indigenous Housing (SOMIH), Community Housing (CH) and Indigenous Community Housing (ICH). The AIHW managed the NSHS in 2005, 2007, 2010, 2012, 2014, 2016, 2018, 2021 and 2023. There have been changes to the methodology for the NSHS over time. However, minimal changes have been made to the survey since 2012 to support time-series analysis.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalStaphylococcusaureusBacteraemiaDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Staphylococcus aureus Bacteraemia Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2009</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Episodes of Staphylococcus aureus (including MRSA and MSSA) bacteraemia (SAB) blood infections in public and participating acute care hospitals.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The data collection includes counts of healthcare associated cases of Staphylococcus aureus bacteraemia (SAB) bloodstream infections for each public hospital covered by SAB surveillance arrangements, and for private hospitals that choose to provide data. The data for public hospitals are collected under hospital infection control arrangements by state and territory health authorities. The data include the counts of patient days under surveillance. Data on the numbers of methicillin- resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) and methicillin-sensitive Staphylococcus aureus (MSSA) cases for public hospitals are reported separately at a hospital and state or territory level.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply)</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Nationalsurveyofchildreninout-ofhomecare-datacollection(2018)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National survey of children in out-of home care - data collection (2018)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/2018</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2018</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">National survey of children aged 8-17 years in out-of-home care. The second collection was held in 2018 (a separate pilot collection was held in in 2015). Data are collected by the state/territory departments responsible for child protection, as part of local case management processes. The dataset includes children's views on various topics, including feelings of safety, participation in decision-making, community connection and activity, family connection and contact, presence of a significant adult in their life, and leaving care.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dataset includes children aged 8–17 years residing in out of-home care (including foster care, relative/kinship care, family group homes, residential care and independent living), whose care arrangements had been ordered by the relevant Children’s Court and where the parental responsibility for the child had been transferred to the Minister or Chief Executive, and who had been on a relevant court order for 3 months or more.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Nationalsurveyofchildreninout-ofhomecare2015</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National survey of children in out-of home care 2015</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/02/2015</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2015</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">National survey of children aged 8-17 years in out-of-home care. This pilot collection was held in 2015. Data are collected by the state/territory departments responsible for child protection, as part of local case management processes. The dataset includes children's views on various topics, including feelings of safety, participation in decision-making, community connection and activity, family connection and contact, presence of a significant adult in their life, and leaving care.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The dataset includes children aged 8–17 years residing in out of-home care (including foster care, relative/kinship care, family group homes, residential care and independent living), whose care arrangements had been ordered by the relevant Children’s Court and where the parental responsibility for the child had been transferred to the Minister or Chief Executive, and who had been on a relevant court order for 3 months or more.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NationalSurveyofLeadinChildren1995</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>National Survey of Lead in Children 1995</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/02/1995</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/03/1995</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The National Survey of Lead in Children1995 was a survey of blood lead concentrations from a nationally representative sample of children aged between 12 and 60 months. The survey was administered in homes and included the collection of blood samples from children, water, house dust and soil samples from these homes, and the administration of a questionnaire to parents. The data collection contains records for 2,886 households and 3,542 children.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The National Survey ofLead in Children 1995 was a survey of blood lead concentrations from a nationally representative sample of children aged between 12 and 60 months. The survey was administered in homes and included the collection of blood samples from children, water, house dust and soil samples from these homes, and the administration of a questionnaire to parents. The data collection contains records for 2,886 households and 3,542 children.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, there arerestrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NursingHome</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Nursing Home</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1988</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: TBA</description>
         <description type="full">Unknown&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unknown</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/NursingHomes(Pre1997Reforms)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Nursing Homes (Pre 1997 Reforms)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#N</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1901</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/1997</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Administrative by product from nursing home payment systems prior to the Aged Care Act 1997. In this domain there were two systems - the 'new' nursing home system (1/7/1995) and the 'old' payment system (ONHPS) prior to 1/7/1995.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Unknown</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/OnlineServicesReport(OSR)forFirstNations–specificprimaryhealthcare</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Online Services Report (OSR) for First Nations – specific primary health care</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#O</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2008</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The OSR is reported by organisations receiving funding under the Australian Government's Indigenous Australians’ Health Programme (IAHP) to deliver comprehensive and culturally appropriate primary health care services to Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander (First Nations) people. It contains contextual information about each organisation as well as aggregate counts of number of clients, episodes of care and FTEs. Prior to 2018-19, the OSR also included data collected from organisations funded by the Department of Health and/or the Department of Prime Minister and Cabinet (function now sitting within the National Indigenous Australians Agency (NIAA)) to provide one or more of the following health services to Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people: primary health care; maternal and child health care (between 2012-13 and 2017-18); social and emotional wellbeing services; and substance-use services.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data on the over 200 organisations funded under the Australian Government's Indigenous Australians’ Health Programme (IAHP). Organisations reporting to the OSR collection may see a mix of First Nations and non Indigenous clients. Data for both First Nations and non-Indigenous clients are included in the OSR collection. Not all clients included in the OSR collection are regular clients of the organisations.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PathwaysinAgedCare(PIAC)linkmap</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Pathways in Aged Care (PIAC) link map</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2022</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Pathways in Aged Care (PIAC) link map is a data asset derived by linking aged care activity data from the National Aged Care Data Clearinghouse (NACDC) and death records from the National Death Index (NDI). It includes activity data for home support, home care, residential care, transition care and aged care eligibility assessments. PIAC is suitable for person-based analysis of aged care pathways and patterns of program use over time. It links data from different aged care programs that do not use a common person identifier, enabling people’s care use to be tracked across services. Derived analysis data sets are available for recipient demographics, event sequence and service locations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The PIAC link map includes all people who used Australian Government-funded aged care services – including home support, home care, residential care, transition care, short term restorative care and aged care eligibility assessments – between 1 July 1997 and 30 June 2022. It includes death records for anyone in the cohort who died between 1 July 1997 and 31 December 2022.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PerinatalMentalHealthpilot(PMHp)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Perinatal Mental Health pilot (PMHp)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/09/2020</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">The Perinatal Mental Health pilot (PMHp) is a novel collection of de-identified antenatal and postnatal mental health data about mothers and other parents collected from public hospitals and maternal and child family health clinics. It includes patients’ self-reported responses to a range of clinical tools.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data is collected fromthe Centre of Perinatal Excellence (COPE) iCOPE digital perinatal mental health screening platform , and data supplied directly from state and territory health departments. This first phase of the data collection only covers a segment of the antenatal and postnatal mental health screening occurring in Australia.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply); Unit records are not available; There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PharmaceuticalBenefitsScheme(PBS)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme (PBS) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/02/1984</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme (PBS) data collection contains information on prescription medicines that qualify for a benefit under the National Health Act 1953 and for which a claim has been processed. The database comprises information about PBS scripts and payments, patients, prescribers and dispensing pharmacies. AIHW has access to a view of the data held by the Australian Government Department of Health and Aged Care for approved studies, including data linkage projects (see AIHW Data Integration Services Centre). The dataset is owned and managed by the Department of Health and Aged Care. The Department has issued a Public Interest Certificate approving AIHW access to PBS claims and under co-payment data for research and statistical purposes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;PBS claims data are an administrative by product of Services Australia administration of the subsidised prescription payment system. PBS prescriptions are available to all Australian residents who hold a current Medicare card and overseas visitors from countries with which Australia has a Reciprocal Health Care Agreement (RHCA).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics. Unit records are not available and there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes – Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PracticeIncentivesProgramQualityImprovementEligibleDataSet</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Practice IncentivesProgram Quality Improvement Eligible Data Set</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National; Other</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2020</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The PIP Eligible Data Set consists of de identified aggregate primary care data on specific Improvement Measures collected and shared by 31 Primary Health Networks (PHNs). The de-identified data is analysed and reported at both regional and national levels to inform broader public health policy, strategic planning and service delivery. The findings of the PIP Eligible Data Set supports the implementation, management, and ongoing development of the PIPQI Incentive program. The data set provides valuable insight into the improvement in quality of primary care and patient outcomes across key health priority areas. It also plays a vital role in informing and shaping regional health care planning, service delivery, and national health policies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The PIP Eligible DataSet only includes de identified aggregate data on specified Improvement Measures. It is collected and provided by 31 Primary Health Networks (PHNs; non Government organisations) from around 5,531 general practices participating in the PIP QI Incentive program within each PHN. Any other data shared by a general practice with a third party falls outside the scope of this Framework. Public reporting includes QIM specific proportions, numerators and denominators at national and PHN levels. For more information on the data scope and Quality Improvement Measures, please refer to the 'External links and information' section.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age group; Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PrivateHospitalDataBureau(PHDB)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Private Hospital Data Bureau (PHDB) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2010</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2021</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The PHDB data collection is a legislated data collection of de-identified information for all separations in private hospitals and day facilities. The data is collected and then submitted to the Department of Health and Aged Care, who in turn supplies de identified information on all private hospital separations to the AIHW.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The PHDB data collection contains de identified information on all private hospital separations, including patient demographics, hospital episode, clinical information, and hospital charges for all patients in private hospitals and day facilities.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PrivateRentAssistancedata(PRA)collection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Private Rent Assistance data (PRA) collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The PRA data collection captures information about the recipients of PRA and instances of PRA assistance. PRA is administered by each state/territory housing authority and provides a range of financial assistance to enable eligible households to access and maintain accommodation in the private rental market. Since 1997–98, the AIHW has compiled PRA data from states and territories annually. The data help to describe the performance of the current National Housing and Homelessness Agreement and the former National Affordable Housing Agreement and Commonwealth State Housing Agreement. The data collection has evolved over time, including changes to data collection scope, procedures, data items collected and underlying definitions and concepts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Relates to the provision of financial assistance to enable households to access and maintain accommodation in the private rental market. Includes: bond loans, rental grants, rental subsidies, relocation expenses and other assistance grants. Excludes: • non-financial assistance, for example, tenancy support services and tenancy guarantees any expense incurred in providing assistance to a household that is not the value of the financial assistance received directly by the household.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PublicdentalwaitingtimesNMDS</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Public dental waiting times NMDS</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">NSW; VIC; QLD; WA; SA; TAS; ACT; NT</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2013</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The PDWT NMDS enables reporting onthe length of time that patients wait for public dental care in Australia, and the characteristics of patients who receive care or who were listed for care in a reference period.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scope of the datacollection is all people eligible for their state or territory public dental scheme, who were aged 18 years or over when they were placed on a general or prosthetic public dentistry waiting list for the purpose of receiving treatment. The data collection includes: • all people specified above with a listing date for dental care within the collection period • all people specified above with a date of offer of dental care within the collection period • all people specified above with a date of first dental visit within the collection period. The data collection excludes: • people who access their local public dental clinic but pay full price and are not eligible for their state or territory's public dental service • people who are treated under jurisdictional priority client schemes (which can be the majority of clients treated in some jurisdictions). • treatments which do not result in removal from a waiting list, such as: - relief of pain that does not satisfy other dental treatment needs emergency treatment that does not satisfy other dental treatment needs.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; SEIFA</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/PublicHousing(PH)andStateOwnedandManagedIndigenousHousing(SOMIH)datacollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Public Housing (PH) and State Owned and Managed Indigenous Housing (SOMIH) data collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#P</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1995</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The PH and SOMIH data collection captures information about PH and SOMIH dwellings and the tenants assisted. Public housing encompasses the publicly owned or leased dwellings funded and administered by state and territory governments. State owned and managed Indigenous housing is administered by state and territory governments and is specifically targeted to Indigenous households (a household with at least 1 Indigenous member). Currently SOMIH operates in New South Wales, Queensland, South Australia, Tasmania, and the Northern Territory. The PH and SOMIH data collection has evolved over time. Changes have occurred to the data collection scope, procedures, data items and underlying definitions and concepts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Includes informationabout PH and SOMIH dwellings and households residing in PH and SOMIH dwellings where the dwelling is: • owned by the housing authority • leased from the private sector or other housing program areas and used for provision of PH and SOMIH programs. Excludes information about PH and SOMIH dwellings and households residing in PH and SOMIH dwellings where the dwelling is: • owned by the state/territory housing authority but leased to other program areas, such as community housing or crisis and emergency accommodation programs, • no longer under the administration of the state/territory housing authority at 30 June (including dwellings demolished, sold or disposed of), and • not yet available to the state/territory housing authority at 30 June, (for example, those under construction or being purchased).</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/QualityinAustralianHealthCareStudy(QAHCS)ReanalysedDatabase</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Quality in Australian Health Care Study (QAHCS) Reanalysed Database</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#Q</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">NSW; SA</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1992</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/1992</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Survey</description>
         <description type="full">QAHCS comprised a review of medical records of over 14,000 admissions in Australian hospitals in 1992, and estimation of the proportion of hospital separations associated with adverse events. For the purposes of the study, an adverse event was defined as an unintended injury or complication which results in disability, death or prolonged hospital stay, and is caused by health care management (rather than the patient's disease). Data on each adverse event identified in the review is contained in the database including information on the nature of the harm experienced by the patient and its consequences, and information on the circumstances in which the harm occurred.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;QAHCS involved review of hospital medical records for 14,179 admissions to 28 hospitals in New South Wales and South Australia in 1992.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/RadiotherapywaitingtimesDSSpilotcollection2013-15</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Radiotherapy waiting times DSS pilot collection 2013- 15</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#R</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2013</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2015</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The main purpose of the Radiotherapy waiting times data set specification (RWT DSS) is to describe the information that must be collected to calculate the waiting times for the following time period in the treatment pathway for radiotherapy services in Australia: the time between the patient's ready-for-care date and the date of the first megavoltage external beam radiotherapy treatment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Establishments in scope are those healthcare establishments that provide megavoltage external beam radiotherapy treatment (in- scope radiotherapy treatment). Both public and private establishments are in scope. While it is mandatory for public establishments to report data to the collection, private providers are also encouraged to participate. The scope is not limited by patient diagnosis: it includes people with cancer (notifiable and non-notifiable) and people who do not have cancer. People in scope are those who started a course of radiotherapy treatment within the reference period. For public establishments, all in scope activity should be reported, including services provided by specialists operating under right of private practice arrangements.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/ResidentialAgedCare</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Residential Aged Care</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#R</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/1999</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2012</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">This database contains administrative by product data for residential aged care since the Aged Care System Reforms of 1997. This is the source of data on residential aged care that is published in the AIHW Aged Care Statistics series. The data base consists of a selection of files from the DoHAC warehouse -ACCMIS (Aged and Community Care Management Information System). From 2013, this collection is effectively inactive, as relevant data are included in the National Aged Care Data Clearinghouse.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All residents in residential aged care at the 1997 change and new admissions since then. The payment system from which the data is derived was developed from the Nursing home payment system. Consequently, a fuller history of clients with nursing home exposure is available but in general pre reform hostel detail is not available through ACCMIS.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: N/A</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/RiskFactorPrevalenceSurveyDataCollection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Risk Factor Prevalence Survey Data Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#R</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/05/1980</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/06/1989</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">There were three Risk Factor Prevalence Surveys (RFPS) run in 1980, 1983 and 1989. These surveys gathered information about the prevalence of heart disease risk factors in adult Australians living in State and Territory capital cities. The surveys gathered self-reported health and demographic information, measured height, weight and blood pressure and collected blood samples for analysis. In all three surveys the blood samples were tested for total cholesterol, HDL cholesterol and triglyceride levels. For the 1989 survey additional analysis of the blood samples was carried out to test blood iron, ferritin and transferrin levels.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For the 1980 and 1983 survey participants were adults aged 25- 64 years randomly selected from the electoral roll and recruited from defined catchment areas in the 6 State capitals. Canberra and Darwin were excluded. For the 1989 survey participants were adults aged 20-69 years recruited from defined catchment areas in the 6 State capitals, as well as Canberra and Darwin.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/SpecialistHomelessnessServicesCollection(SHSC)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Specialist Homelessness Services Collection (SHSC)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#S</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2011</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The SHSC collects information about people who are referred to, or seek assistance from, specialist homelessness services (SHS) agencies. These services collect the data on an ongoing basis and are responsible for submitting the data to the AIHW on a monthly basis. There are two parts to the SHSC — a Client collection and an Unassisted Persons collection. • The Client collection captures information on adults and children who receive a service from an SHS agency. • The Unassisted Person collection is used to gain information about adults and children whose request for service is not able to be met by an SHS agency.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Client collection - The base unit is a person who presents to an SHS agency requesting services. A person becomes a ‘client’ once they receive a service(s). A ‘support period’ is the period of time a client receives assistance from a SHS agency. It relates to the provision of a service and/or supported accommodation. During a support period, a range of services additional to supported accommodation can be provided. Detail on types of services provided is also available. Unassisted persons collection - Comprises information on the number of instances where a person received no immediate services from a SHS agency. Details of all agencies participating in the SHSC are on the Specialist Homelessness Establishment Database file. Information is submitted to the AIHW monthly.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status; RA; SA2; SA3; SA4; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Data cubes, Summary tables published in electronic form, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/SupportedAccommodationAssistanceProgramData</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Supported Accommodation Assistance Program Data</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#S</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/1996</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2011</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Specialist Homelessness Services Collection (SHSC) replaced the SAAP National Data Collection (NDC) on 1 July 2011. For key differences between the&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The scope of SAAP NDC data varied by collection component and over time. For more</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Statistics, Client specified tables on</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Collection</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Collection</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#C</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text"/>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: </description>
         <description type="full">SAAP NDC and SHSC, see Appendix Dof Specialist Homelessness Services 2011– 12 (AIHW website). The SAAP NDC provided nationally consistent information on SAAP clients and services from July 1996 to June 2011. It was jointly funded by Commonwealth, state and territory governments and comprised three main collections: • Client collection – the main component, captured socio demographic information about clients receiving support under SAAP, services required by and provided to each client, and client circumstances before and after receiving support. • Demand for accommodation collection – which operated over a 1-week period, twice yearly. It captured information about the number of people who requested accommodation at SAAP agencies, which requests were met, and reasons for this. • Administrative collection – collated from information obtained by state and territory government departments in the course of administering the SAAP program. It captured descriptive information about SAAP agencies. The following special issues collections were also undertaken as part of the SAAP NDC: • Casual client collection – discontinued from the SAAP NDC in June 2005 when the definitions of client and support period were changed so that many people previously counted as casual clients would be counted in the Client collection from 1 July 2005. • Accompanying child in SAAP collection – collected information about the children who accompanied an adult and received assistance under SAAP between 21 May and 30 June 1998. • Income issues collection – collected information on SAAP clients with no/very low income. It was conducted from May to June 2000. A number of methodological changes to the SAAP NDC occurred over time. Refinements to data items introduced in July each year are summarised in the annual reports for the data collection, available from the AIHW website. In particular, in 2005–06 a Core Data Set was introduced (collecting fewer data items, introducing a new statistical linkage key and incorporating changes to some definitions) and from 2000–01, the Client Collection captured demographic and support information for each child requiring assistance. The AIHW continues to hold data collected through the following surveys of SAAP agencies conducted by the AIHW outside of the SAAP NDC: • High and complex needs census (June 2008). • Youth homelessness pilot programme collection (1 July 1997 to 31 December 1999). • NSW access and exiting project collection (23 August to 1 September 2002). Access to SAAP data collected outside of the SAAP NDC is restricted.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;information, refer to the annual reports for the data collection, available from the AIHW website.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply)., There are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/SurveyofOccupationalExposuresAmongTrainedADFPersonnel</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Survey of Occupational Exposures Among Trained ADF Personnel</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#S</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Survey data set comprises a potentially valuable source of data for future research on: 1. The self-reported types and levels of occupational exposure of trained personnel serving in a range of roles to specific factors known to be associated with increased risk of individuals developing a variety of health conditions; 2. Incidence rates and body sites of self reported musculoskeletal injuries (by level of severity) and external burns among trained personnel serving in a range of roles; 3. Prevalence rates, durations and constancy of self reported tinnitus symptoms among trained personnel serving in a range of roles; and 4. The range of chemical exposures reported by trained personnel serving in a variety of roles.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth)</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement/>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Totalincidenceofend-stagekidneydisease(ESKD)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Total incidence of end-stage kidney disease (ESKD)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#T</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/01/1997</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">31/12/2013</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">Monitoring of the total incidence of ESKD in Australia, by linking ANZDATA registry data with the AIHW National Death Index to count cases treated and not treated with kidney replacement therapy (KRT).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Patients with ESKD whoare treated and not treated with KRT. Demographic and causes of death information available.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Client specified tables on request which may be subject to data provider approval (charges apply), Unit records are not available</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/Youngerpeoplewithdisabilityinresidentialagedcare(YPIRAC)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Younger people with disability in residential aged care (YPIRAC)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#Y</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2006</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2011</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data; Official</description>
         <description type="full">The Younger people with disability in residential aged care (YPIRAC) program was agreed by the Council of Australian Governments (COAG) on 10 February 2006 with the aim of delivering sustained reductions in the number of younger people with disability in residential aged care. The YPIRAC program operated under a 5- year agreement between the Australian Government and state and territory governments. The program was funded through the states and territories and administered by the Australian Government Department of Families, Housing, Community Services, and Indigenous Affairs (FaHCSIA). The AIHW was contracted by FaHCSIA to develop a YPIRAC Minimum Data Set (MDS), and to complete the MDS over the 5-year collection periods. YPIRAC data collected concluded in 2010-11.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All state and territory governments provide data on the YPIRAC program.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, there are restrictions and limitations governing the availability or use of other data in this holding.</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights>Yes - Restricted access</accessRights>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/YourExperienceofServicesurveyDatabase(MentalHealth)</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Your Experience of Service survey Database (Mental Health)</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#Y</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National and State</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2015</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF"/>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Survey</description>
         <description type="full">Survey data where consumers rate their experience of service on several domains.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;State and territory public sector specialised mental health services.</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Age (Date of birth); Sex/gender; Statistical Linkage Key</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
   <registryObject group="Australian Institute of Health and Welfare">
      <key>AIHW/YouthJustice</key>
      <originatingSource>http://aihw.gov.au</originatingSource>
      <collection type="collection">
         <name type="primary">
            <namePart>Youth Justice</namePart>
         </name>
         <location>
            <address>
               <electronic type="url">
                  <value>https://www.aihw.gov.au/about-our-data/our-data-collections#Y</value>
               </electronic>
            </address>
         </location>
         <coverage>
            <spatial type="text">National</spatial>
            <temporal>
               <date type="dateFrom" dateFormat="W3CDTF">01/07/2000</date>
               <date type="dateTo" dateFormat="W3CDTF">30/06/2023</date>
            </temporal>
         </coverage>
         <description type="lineage">Methodology: Admin data</description>
         <description type="full">The Youth Justice National Minimum Data Set (YJ NMDS) is an annual collection of information on young people under youth justice supervision in Australia. It contains data on all supervised orders (both community based and detention) relating to young people under youth justice supervision.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;All young people underyouth justice supervision throughout Australia from July 2000</description>
         <description type="note">Variables to support reporting and linkage: Indigenous status</description>
         <rights type="rights">
            <rightStatement>Publications, Summary tables published in electronic form, Restricted unit record access subject to Ethics Committee approval and/or the agreement of all relevant data custodians in all states and territories (charges may apply).</rightStatement>
         </rights>
         <rights>
            <accessRights/>
         </rights>
      </collection>
   </registryObject>
</registryObjects>
